Fernando Arriagada

Senior Front-End Developer / Full-Stack Developer

Santiago, Chile (GMT-3) (+56) 9 99412410 farriagadal94@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/fernando-arriagada https://farriagadal.site

Senior Front-End Developer with +4 years of experience in the area of web development with Javascript and Typescript (React.js, Vue.js and Angular). I have worked in technology consulting companies, marketing agencies and start-ups. I have solid knowledge in development technologies such as Docker, Git, Jira, AWS. Motivated by creating IT solutions and developing myself both as a person and as a professional. I am looking for new challenges with cutting-edge technologies (Consultancies and/or Start-ups), where I can continue to grow as a Front-end Engineer and work remotely.

EXPERIENCE

NTTDATA, React Senior Developer — March, 2022 - Present

- I led the integration with Google Looker and React.js for the visualization of dashboards for LATAM Airlines, which meant the renewal of the client's contract with the company thanks to the good results.
- I led the Front-End development of a web platform in React.js for administration and management of medical staff of "Clinica Las Condes".
- I increased the coverage of Unit Tests from 20% to 80% of Front-End in React.js of the existing web platform of "Clínica Alemana".

Technology Stack: React.js, Next.js.

MEAT Group, Semi-Senior Front-End Developer — September, 2020 - March, 2022

- Developed a web platform for the supervision and management of THE LINE branches. Implemented unit tests with Jest.
- I developed the ticketing platform for the "Teatro Municipal de Santiago", where I led the integration with the ticketing API. The development was done in Nuxt.js for SEO optimization.
- I developed a wordpress plugin to add OpenStreetMaps maps with the location of the stores.
- Maintenance of Banco de Chile App in Vue.js and compilation for mobile devices (Android and iOS) with Cordova.
- Other developments and maintenance of websites and web apps.

 Tach a large Starley Vision New tip Popular Words years I ground Control of the Popular Words and Starley W

Technology Stack: Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React.js, Docker, Wordpress, Laravel, Cordova.

Opting IT Solutions, Software Engineer — September, 2018 - June, 2020

- I led an agile cell as Scrum Master.
- I maintained a close relationship with clients for requirements documentation and presentation of progress.
- I collaborated in the training of new developers suggesting courses, with pair-coding development and reviewing the code according to development methodologies and best practices.
- I collaborated in the development of different custom software for clients.

Technological stack: Angular 10, Docker, Wordpress, Python, PostgreSQL.

GTD Consulting Engineers, Memorist — January, 2018 - April, 2018

• I developed a mathematical algorithm in Python for the automation of earthworks studies. The software was used in several projects with excellent results.

Technological stack: Python, GIS.

<u>SKILLS</u>

Programming languages: Advanced: Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS; Intermediate: Python. Básico: PHP.

Frameworks: Advanced: React.js, Vue.js, Next.js; Intermediate: Angular, Django.

Databases: Intermediate: MySQL, PostgreSQL; Basic: MongoDB.

Other Tools: Git, Trello, Jira, Confluence, Slack, AWS. Languages: Intermediate: Inglés; Native: Español.

EDUCATION

University San Sebastián – Santiago, Chile. Software Engineer, February 2018.

University San Sebastián - Santiago, Chile. Bachelor of Science in Engineering, February 2015.

CERTIFICATIONS

Course of Advanced React.js – Platzi, Educational technology company. 2021.

Course of Testing with Vue.js - Platzi, Educational technology company. 2021.

Introduction to Python programming – Universidad Católica de Chile. 2020.

Programming with JavaScript ED6 - Movistar Chile. 2020.

Scrum Master Accredited Certification – International Scrum Institute. 2020.